44 chapter 45 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 45 Jerry's New
Year For some people Christmas and the New Year are very mer times; but for
cabmen and cab men's horses it is no holiday, though it may be a harvest. There
are so many parties, balls, and places of amusement open for the work is hard and often
late. Sometimes driver and horse have to wait for hours in the rain or frost,
shivering with the cold, while the merry people within are dancing away to the
music. I wonder if the beautiful ladies ever think of the weary cabman waiting
on his box, and his patient beast standing, till his legs get stiff with
cold. I had now most of the evening work, as I was well accustomed to standing, and
Jerry was also more afraid of Hotspur taking cold. We had a great deal of late
work in the Christmas week, and Jerry's cough was bad; but however late we were,
Polly sat up for him, and came out with a lantern to meet him, looking anxious ious and
troubled. On the evening of the New Year we had to take two gentlemen to a house
in one of the West End Squares. We set
them down at 9:00 and we told to come
again at 11: but,” said one, “as it is a
card party, you may have to wait a few minutes, but don't be
late.” As the clock struck 11 we were at the door, for Jerry was always punctual.
The clock chimed the quarters 1 2 3 and then struck 12 but the door did not
open. The wind had been very changeable, with squalls of wind during the day, but
now it came on sharp, driving sleep which seemed to come all the way around it was
very cold, and there was no shelter. Jerry got off his box and came and pulled one
of my cloths a little more over my neck;
then he took a turn or two up and down, stamping his feet; then he began to beat
his arms, but that set him off coughing; so he opened the cab door and sat at the
bottom with his feet on the pavement, and was a little sheltered. Still the clock chimed the
quarters, and no one came. At half 12 he rang the bell and asked the servant if
he would be wanted that night. “Oh, yes, you'll be wanted safe enough,” said the
man; “you must not go, it will soon be over,” and again Jerry sat down, but his voice
was so horar I could hardly hear him. At a qu 1 the door opened, and the
two gentlemen came out; they got into the cab with without a word, and told Jerry
where to drive, that was nearly 2 miles.
My legs were numb with cold, and I thought I should have
stumbled. When the men got out they never said they were sorry to have kept us
waiting so long, but were angry at the charge; however, as Jerry never charged
more than was his due, so he never took
less, and they had to pay for the 2 hours and a quarter waiting; but it was hard
earned money to Jerry. At last we got home; he could hardly speak, and his was dreadful. Polly
asked no questions, but opened the door and held the lantern for him. “Can't I do
something?” she said. “Yes; get Jack something warm, and then boil me some
GRL This was said in a horse whisper; he could hardly get his breath, but he gave
me a rub down as usual, and even went up into the hoft for an extra bundle of
straw for my bed. Polly brought me a warm mash that made me comfortable, and then
they locked the door.
It was late the next morning before anyone came, and then it was only Harry.
He cleaned us and fed us, and swept out the stalls, then he put the straw back
again as if it was Sunday. He was very still, and neither whistled nor
[Music]
sang. At noon he came again and gave us our food and water; this time Dolly came
with him; she was crying, and I could gather from what they said that Jerry
was dangerously ill, and the doctor said it was a bad case.
So two days passed, and there was great trouble indoors. We only saw Harry, and sometimes
Dolly. I think she came for company, for Polly was always with Jerry, and he had
to be kept very quiet. On the third day, while Harry was
in the stable, a tap came at the door, and Governor Grant came in. “I wouldn't go to
the house, my boy,” he said, “but I want to know how your father
is.” “He is very bad,” said Harry, “he can't be much worse; they call it 'bronchitis'; the
doctor thinks it will turn one way or another tonight That's bad, very bad,” said Grand
shaking his head; “I know two men have died of that last week; it takes them
often no time; but while there's life there's hope, so you must keep up your
spirits.” “Yes,” said Harry quickly, “and the doctor said that father had a better
chance than most men, because he didn't drink. He said yesterday the fever was so
high that if father had been a drinking man it would have burned him up like a
piece of paper; but I believe he thinks he will get over it; don't you think he
will, Mr.
Grant?” The governor looked puzzled. “If there's any rule that good
men should get over these things, I'm sure he will, my boy; he's the best man I
know. I'll look in early tomorrow Early next morning he was there.
“Well?” said he. “Father is better,” said Harry.
“Mother hopes he will get over it.” “Thank God!” said the governor, “and now you must
keep him warm, and keep his mind easy, and that brings me to the
horses; you see Jack will be all the better for the rest of a week or two in
a warm stable, and you can easily take him a turn up and down the street to
stretch his legs; but this young one, if he does not get work, he will soon be all
up on end, as you may say, and will be
rather too much for you; and when he does go out there'll be an
accident.” “It is like that now,” said said Harry I've kept him short of corn, but
he's so full of spirit I don't know what to do with
him.” “Just so,” said gr Now look here, will you tell your mother that if she is
agreeable I will come for him every day till something is arranged, and take him
for a good spell of work, and whatever he earns, I'll bring your mother half of it,
and that will help with the horse's feed.
Your father is in a good club, I know, but that won't keep the horses, and they'll
be eating their heads off all this time; I'll come at noon and hear what she says,”
and without waiting for Harry's thanks he was gone. At noon I think he went and saw
Polly, for he and Harry came to the stable together, harnessed Hotspur, and took him
out. For a week or more he came for Hotspur, and when Harry thanked him or
said anything about his kindness, he laughed it off, saying it was all good
luck for him, for his horses were wanting a little rest which they would not have otherwise
had. Jerry grew better steadily, but the doctor said he must never go back to the
cab work again if he wished to be an old man. The children had many consultations
together about what father and mother would do, and how they could help to earn
money. One afternoon Hots spur was brought in very wet and
dirty. “The streets are nothing but slush,” said the governor; “it will give you a
good warming, my boy, to get him clean and dry.” “All right, governor,” said Harry, “I
shall not leave him till he is; you know I have been trained by my father.”
“I wish all the boys had been trained like you,” said the governor. While Harry was sponging off
the mud from Hotspur's body and legs Dolly came in, looking very full of
something. “Who lives at fairo Harry?
Mother has a letter from FAO she seemed so glad, and ran upstairs to father with
it.” “Don't you know? Why, it is the name of Mrs. Fowler's place— —mother's old mistress,
you know— —the lady that father met last summer, who sent you and me five shillings each.”
“Oh! Mrs. Fowler. Of course, I know all about her. I wonder what she's writing to mother
about.” “Mother wrote to her last week,” said Harry; “you know she told father if ever
he gave up the cab work she would like to know. I wonder what she says; run in
and see, Dolly.” Harry scrubbed away at Hotspur with a like any old
hosler In a few minutes Dolly came dancing into the stable. “Oh oh Harry, there was never
anything so beautiful; Mrs. Fowler says we are all to go and live near her. There is
a cottage now empty that will just suit us, with a garden and a hen house and
apple trees and everything! and her coachman is going away in the spring, and
then she will want father in his place; and there are good families around where
you can get a place in the garden or the
stable, or as a page boy and it's a good school for me; and mother is laughing and
crying by turns, and father does look so happy!” “That's uncommon jolly,” said Harry,
“and just the right thing, I should say; it will suit father and mother both; but I
don't intend to be a page boy with tight clothes and rows of buttons. I'll be a
groom or a gardener.” It was quickly settled that as soon as Cherry was well enough they
should remove to the country, and that the cab and horses should be sold as soon as
possible. This was heavy news for me, for I was not young now, and could not look
for any improvement in my condition. Since I left Berwick I had
never been so happy as with my dear master Jerry; but 3 years of cab work,
even under the best conditions, will tell on one's strength, and I felt that I was
not the horse that I had once been. Grant said at once that he would
take Hotspur, and there were men on the stand who would have bought me; but Jerry
said I should not go to cab work again with just anybody, and the governor
promised to find a place for me where I should be comfortable. The day came for going away.
Jerry had not been allowed to go out yet, and I never saw him after that New
Year's eve. Polly and the children came to bid me goodbye Poor old Jack! dear old Jack! I
wish we could take you with us,” she said, and then laying her hand on my man she
put her face close to my neck and kissed me. Dolly was crying and kissed me too.
Harry stroked me a great deal, but said nothing, only he seemed very sad, and so
so I was led away to my new place end of chapter 45 end of part